Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/nguyen-dang-245414226 (LinkedIn)

Nguyen Dang

Software Engineer Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

Summary -----SUMMARY

I am a Software Engineer with six years of experience in developing software. I have professional skills, hard skills, and soft skills to get the job done and done effectively and with quality. I also have leadership, and I am currently a team leader for a group of junior software engineers. Finally, I have a lot of experience with different domains, programming languages, and professional tools relative to development.

SKILLS

- * Professional skills:
- Be able to understand, communicate, collaborate, and elicit not only business requirements but also technical requirements.
- Be able to understand and apply processes standards, design patterns, best practices, etc. to perform tickets, tasks, testing, debugging, etc. (MVC, SOLID principle, Atomic,...)
- Experience working with different Software Development Life Cycles such as Waterfall and Agile (Scrum, Banban).
- Be able to understand and publish technical documents such as API, XML, Software Spec, and Functional Spec.
- Have good knowledge of UIUX and best practice for improving user experiences and working with professional tools such as Figma, Adobe xd, Clipchamp, etc.
- Strong analytical skills to visualize data flow using sequence diagrams, process flow, and strong critical thinking for problem-solving, and planning.
- * Soft skills:
- Communication in English and Vietnamese.
- Strong, ambitious, enthusiastic personality.

- Dynamic, strategic with good business acumen.
- Being a proactive and assertive individual with well-developed leadership qualities.
- Demonstrated commitment to personal development.
- Very friendly, and instinctive to care and take care of team members.
- A team influencer and trusted partner.
- Team building and strong self-motivational skills as well as the ability to work independently.
- Quick learner and active listener.
- * Hard skills:
- Language: Javascript, Typescript, Python, Java, HTML/CSS, Go
- Framework and Library: NodeJS, NextJS, Sprint, ReactJS, Material-UI, Ant Design, Bootstrap, Schema Json (Google), etc.
- Architecture and Infrastructure: Monolithic, Microservices, Cloud computing, etc.
- Professional tools: Github, Gitlab, Postman, SoapUI, Jira, Trello, Azure DevOps, Visual Studio Code, IntelliJ IDEA, etc.

Experience

OPSWAT

2 years 2 months

Senior Software Engineer October 2023 - Present (1 year 6 months)

Join the MyOPSWAT Product Management team, where I take on a multifaceted role:

- Innovating, developing, and maintaining products.
- Collaborating with OPSWAT products and stakeholders on new features.
- Technical expertise:
- ++ Backend: Go, Java
- ++ Front-end: React, Angular

Additionally, I research and develop automation test repositories, integrating new technologies into CI/CD pipelines.

- Automation Testing: Playwright, TypeScript

Middle Software Engineer
June 2023 - October 2023 (5 months)

This blend of responsibilities enables me to lead the Front-end Team effectively while actively contributing to feature development and system integration across the tech stack.

Software Engineer

February 2023 - June 2023 (5 months)

Vietnam

As the Front-end Lead of the MyOPSWAT Portal Team, I:

- Collaborate with Business Analysts to understand customer needs.
- Work with Designers to ensure seamless UI/UX.
- Integrate third-party services like OpenAI.
- Develop with ReactJS, NodeJS, NestJS, and GraphQL.

Hahalolo Travel Social Network Software Engineer February 2020 - February 2023 (3 years 1 month) Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

- I am a skilled Software Engineer with experience in web design and development.
- I led a team of six junior engineers through the software development life cycle for Hahalolo projects, driving innovation and fostering new technical skills within the team.
- Technical: React, NestJS

Tradeline Viet Nam Software Engineer February 2020 - February 2023 (3 years 1 month) Vietnam

- I am a skilled Software Engineer with experience in web design and development.
- I join through the software development life cycle for Tradeline projects, driving innovation and fostering new technical skills within the team.
- Technical: NextJS, ReactJS

Education

Van Lang University

Computer Software Engineering · (2017 - 2021)